Laubach Literacy International Records
Laubach Literacy International Records
- Laubach, Robert S.
  - Literacy journalism papers
    - Stauffer, John M. & Malcolm Campbell / The Problem: Illiteracy in the U.S (Box 393)
    - Stein, Wendy
      - Ladder of Literacy for the Elderly in the United States (Box 393)
      - The Christmas Story (Box 393)
    - Study of adult literacy organizations in Syracuse: LVA/NALA, Dec. 1978 (Box 449)
    - Tabler, Myrle Evelyn / Survey of production by Seventh Day Adventists of easy reading materials for new adult readers, June 1970 (Box 449)
    - Tucker, Bert O. / Frank C. Laubach: Selected Quotations on Techniques in Adult Literacy (Box 393)
    - Weeks, Douglas / Religious Magazines--Are They Interesting? (Box 393)
    - Wendell, Margaret / Producing Literacy Materials in a Pre-Literate Society (Box 393)
    - Wolde, Menbere
      - Adult Literacy in Ethiopia (Box 393)
      - Four Approaches to Communications Analysis (Box 393)
      - A Study of Christian Book Appeal to Protestants in Ethiopia (Box 394)
    - Wolseley, Roland / Journalism school started with one book (India) (Box 449)
    - Woods, Murden / Sample survey of the availability, amount, comparative quality of publications for new literates in north India, in Hindi, 1956 (Box 449)
    - Yen, Gordon / Ladder of Literacy (Box 394)
    - Yost, Donald / Controversy & the Church Magazine: A Study of Readership, Church-relatedness, & Age (Box 394)
    - Bibliographies, Literacy, 1963-1975 (Box 394)
    - Book reports, A-H (alphabetical by student's last name) (Box 394)
    - Book reports, I-Z (alphabetical by student's last name) (Box 394)
    - Periodicals in the field of literacy (Box 394)
  - Meetings, Afro-Lit, Dec. 1972 (Box 387)
  - Memorial Fund, Frank C. Laubach, 1971-1977 (Box 387)
  - Memorial Fund, Frank C. Laubach, 1970-1972; correspondence (Box 387)
  - Miscellaneous, 1954-1971 (Box 387)
  - National Affiliation for Literacy Advance (NALA)
    - [General], 1972 (Box 387)
    - Executive Committee, Jan. 22-24, 1976 (Box 387)
    - Meetings, June 8-10, 1971; Sept. 28-30, 1972 (Box 387)
  - Personnel, 1968-1974 (Box 395)
  - Personnel goals and objectives, 1971-1972 (Box 395)
  - Personnel; Newland, Phyllis, 1976 (Box 395)
  - Primer manuscripts, various authors, undated (Box 395)
  - Programs, 1970-1976 (Box 395)
  - Reports on Afghanistan, Books for People, Colombia, International Programs, 1965-1972 (Box 395)
  - Reports, International, 1968 (Box 395)
  - Speeches, "Effective Use of Volunteers., 1976 (Box 395)
  - Syracuse City School District, Reading Achievement Task Force, 1971-1972 (Box 395)
  - Trustees, Board of, Jan 19-20, 1968 (Box 395)
  - Writers Workshop, July 7-Aug. 2, 1972 (Box 395)
  - Writings, "The New Age of Missions., 1976 (Box 395)
- Laubach Literacy Action (LLA)
  - [General], 1984 (Box 449)
  - Annual council and associate reports, 1984-1985; 8 folders (Box 449)
  - Annual council and associate reports, 1984-1986; 5 folders (Box 450)
  - Awards Committee, 3 folders (Box 450)
  - Committees, 1978-1980 (Box 450)
  - Conferences, biennial, 1986 (Box 450)
  - Correspondence; Waite, Peter, 1983-1985 (Box 450)
  - Directories, 1985-1991; 3 folders (Box 450)
  - Directories, state, 1986 (Box 450)
  - ESOL, 1980 (Box 450)
  - Membership, 1973-1981; 1984 (Box 450)
  - Miscellaneous, 1979 (Box 450)
  - Newsletters
    - Alabama - California, 1976-1985; 5 folders (Box 450)
    - California - Ohio, 1976-1986; 25 folders (Box 451)
    - Ohio - Wisconsin, 1976-1987; 16 folders (Box 452)
    - Miscellaneous, 1986-1988 (Box 452)
  - Organizational game / McFall, Karen, 1982 (Box 452)
  - Proposals, 1985 (Box 452)
  - Public relations (Box 452)
  - Public service announcements, 1983 (Box 452)
  - Recruitment ideas (Box 452)
  - Reports, Indiana, 1987 (Box 452)
  - Schools Tutorial Project publicity, 1976 (Box 452)
  - Steering committee, 1982-1986; 5 folders (Box 452)
  - Steering committee, 1984-1986; 9 folders (Box 453)
  - Training and certification committee, 1983-1984; 2 folders (Box 453)
- National Affiliation for Literacy Advance (NALA)
  - Advanced trainer workshop, Jun. 1978 (Box 453)
  - Advisory Panel, 1973-1977 (Box 395)
  - American Council on Education, 1975-1976 (Box 395)
  - American Council on Education, 1976-1978 (Box 453)
  - Articles, pre-1970 (Box 395)
  - Awards Committee, "Play'n Talk. (Box 395)
  - Awards nominees, 1976 (Box 395)
  - Certification Standards and Training, 1974-1976 (Box 396)
  - Certification Standards and Training, 1976-1978 (Box 453)
  - Chinatown (Box 396)
  - Clark, Edna McConnell Foundation, 1973 (Box 396)
  - Clark, Edna McConnell Foundation, School Tutorial Program, 1975-1976 (Box 396)
  - Committees
    - [General], 1972-1974 (Box 396)
    - Executive, 1978; handbook (Box 453)
    - Finance, 1976-1979 (Box 453)
    - Organizational, 1976-1979 (Box 453)
    - Publications, 1976-1978 (Box 453)
    - Research and evaluation, 1976-1978 (Box 453)
  - Conferences
    - [General], 1976-1978 (Box 453)
    - Biennial, 1984 (Box 453)
    - Stauffer Study, Apr. 19-22, 1972 (Box 453)
  - Constitution and bylaws, 1969-1974 (Box 396)
  - Constitution and bylaws, 1976-1978 (Box 453)
  - Correspondence
    - [General], 1972-1974 (Box 396)
    - [General], 1978 (Box 453)
    - Borei, Swen, 1977-1978 (Box 453)
    - Bagwell, Ben, 1972-1974 (Box 396)
    - Committee Chairmen, 1977-1978 (Box 453)
    - Executive Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 396)
    - French, Ruth, 1973-1975 (Box 396)
    - Hanson, Marilyn, 1977-1978 (Box 453)
    - Jacques, Joseph W., 1976-1978 (Box 453)
    - Kumley, Mary, 1977-1978 (Box 453)
    - Lane, Marti, 1977-1978 (Box 453)
    - Memos, 1972-1973 (Box 396)
    - Roper, Barbara, 1976-1977 (Box 453)
    - Silvia, Addie / Jean Lebedun, 1977-1978 (Box 453)
  - Council Bulletins
    - Alaska, 1975 (Box 396)
    - Arizona, 1971-1975 (Box 396)
    - Arkansas, 1966-1973 (Box 396)
    - Arkansas, Fayetteville, Word at Work, 1968-1975 (Box 397)
    - Arkansas, Little Rock, 1971-1975 (Box 397)
    - California, Anaheim (Southern), 1961-1970 (Box 397)
    - California, Bakersfield (KALC), 1970-1975 (Box 397)
    - California, Belmont and Berkeley, 1968; 1965 (Box 397)
    - California, Fresno, 1973-1975 (Box 397)
    - California, Livermore, 1971-1974 (Box 397)
    - California, North San Diego, 1964-1974 (Box 397)
    - California, Orange County; Santa Clara; Sonoma, 1974-1975 (Box 397)
    - Canada, Nova Scotia, Halifax; Ontario, Hamilton, 1974; 1975 (Box 399)
    - Delaware (Kent Literacy), 1975 (Box 397)
    - District of Columbia (Washington D.C.), 1964-1966 (Box 397)
    - Florida, Dade County; Gainesville; Jacksonville, 1967; 1973-1975 (Box 397)
    - Florida, Orlando, 1968-1975 (Box 397)
    - Florida, St. Petersburg; Titusville, 1971-1975 (Box 397)
    - Georgia, 1968-1974 (Box 397)
    - Hawaii, 1972-1975 (Box 397)
    - Illinois, Chicago; Literacy News and Tutor News, 1969-1975 (Box 398)
    - Illinois, Dekalb; Moline; Rockford, 1969-1976 (Box 398)
    - Indiana, Literacy News, 1965-1972 (Box 398)
    - Indiana, Evansville; Elkhart; Goshen, 1965-1976 (Box 398)
    - Indiana, Fort Wayne, 1968-1975 (Box 398)
    - Indiana, Kokomo; South Bend; Vincennes, 1964-1975 (Box 398)
    - Iowa, Dubuque, 1975 (Box 398)
    - Kansas, Topeka, 1971-1975 (Box 398)
    - Kentucky, Somerset, 1973 (Box 398)
    - Louisiana, Baton Rouge; Operation Upgrade, 1968-1973 (Box 398)
    - Maryland, Montgomery County, See Memorabilia: NALA: Council bulletins: Maryland, Montgomery County, 1964-1975 (Box 426).
    - Maryland, Chevy Chase; Prince George's County, 1965-1966 (Box 398)
    - Massachusetts, Wayland, 1966 (Box 398)
    - Michigan, Adrian; Holland; Lewanee; Michigan Literacy Inc., 1972-1973; 1975 (Box 398)
    - Michigan, Lansing; Three Rivers, 1972-1975 (Box 398)
    - Minnesota, Twin Cities, 1972-1975 (Box 398)
    - Missouri, Columbia; St. Louis; Springfield, 1971-1975 (Box 399)
      See also Memorabilia: NALA: Council bulletins: Missouri, Springfield, 1971-1975.
    - Nebraska, Omaha, 1972-1975 (Box 399)
    - New Jersey, Newark, 1975 (Box 399)
    - New York, Inwood, 1965-1966 (Box 399)
    - North Carolina, Cabarrus; Pitt County; Raleigh, 1968-1976 (Box 399)
    - Ohio, Cincinnati; Cleveland; Columbus, 1973-1975 (Box 399)
    - Ohio, Dayton, 1965-1975 (Box 399)
    - Oklahoma, 1967-1975 (Box 399)
    - Oregon, 1967-1975; See Memorabilia: NALA: Council bulletins: Oregon, Portland (Box 426).
    - Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, 1969-1975 (Box 399)
    - South Carolina, Columbia County; Greenville, 1967; 1969-1975 (Box 399)
    - Tennessee, Knoxville, 1976 (Box 399)
    - Texas, Bellaire; Smith County; Bryan; Houston, 1963-1976 (Box 399)
      See also Memorabilia: NALA: Council bulletins: Texas, Baylor University, Waco; San Antonio (Box 426).
    - Virginia, Alexandria, 1964-1975 (Box 399)
    - Virginia, Hampton; Harrisonburg, 1969-1972 (Box 399)
    - Washington, Auburn; Des Moines; Seattle, 1970-1975 (Box 399)
    - Washington, Tacoma, 1968-1975 (Box 399)
    - Wisconsin, Madison; Racine, 1966-1975 (Box 399)
      See also Memorabilia: NALA: Council bulletins: Wisconsin, Janeville (Box 426).
    - Wisconsin, Milwaukee; Sheboygan, 1968-1975 (Box 399)
  - Curriculum Development Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 400)
  - English to Speakers of Other Languages (ESOL)
    - [General], 1976-1977 (Box 400)
    - [General], 1976-1980 (Box 453)
  - Executive Committee
    - [General], 1969-1974 (Box 400)
    - Handbook, 1975 (Box 400)
    - Minutes, 1970-1972 (Box 400)
    - Minutes, May-June 1975 (Box 400)
  - Field Survey Summaries, 1975-1976 (Box 453)
  - Finance Committee, 1974
  - Flash Cards (Box 400)
  - Handbook, 1976-1978 (Box 454)
  - History (Box 458)
  - International representatives, 1977 (Box 454)
  - LWE/ESOL Training, form letters, 1976 (Box 400)
  - Lilly Foundation, 1972-1973 (Box 400)
  - Lots of Volunteer Effort (LOVE), 1973-1974 (Box 400)
  - LOVE student folder, 1972 (Box 400)
  - Meetings
    - [General], 1972; 1976 (Box 400)
    - [General], 1973-1976 (Box 400)
    - [General], June 21-23, 1973 (Box 400)
    - [General], May 5, 1974 (Box 400)
    - National Conference, 1976 (Box 400)
    - National Conference, Program Committee, 1976 (Box 400)
  - Membership, 1976-1977 (Box 454)
  - Membership forms, certificates, 1968-1976 (Box 401)
  - Metro Projects
    - [General], 1975 (Box 401)
    - [General], 1975-1977 (Box 454)
    - Akron, Ohio, 1973 (Box 401)
    - Albuquerque, New Mexico (Box 401)
    - Anchorage, Alaska, Nov. 1973-May 1976 (Box 401)
    - Anchorage, Alaska, undated; apprentice trainer evaluation (Box 401)
    - Anchorage, Alaska, 1974-1975; training
    - Cleveland, Ohio, Aug. 2 1975-March 1976 (Box 401)
    - Cleveland, Ohio, 1975; apprentice evaluation (Box 401)
    - Cleveland, Ohio, 1974-1975; training (Box 401)
    - Denver, Colorado, 1973-1974 (Box 401)
    - Denver, Colorado, 1975; apprentice evaluations (Box 401)
    - Denver, Colorado, 1974-1976; training (Box 401)
    - Des Moines, Iowa, 1973 (Box 401)
    - El Paso, Texas, 1973 (Box 401)
    - El Paso, Texas, 1975-1976; training (Box 402)
    - Jackson, Mississippi, 1973 (Box 402)
    - Jacksonville, Florida, 1976-1977 (Box 454)
    - Jersey City, New Jersey, circa 1971 (Box 402)
    - Memphis, Tennessee, 1973-1975; undated; 3 folders (Box 402)
    - Memphis, Tennessee, 1974; apprentice trainer evaluation (Box 402)
    - Memphis, Tennessee, 1974; training (Box 402)
    - Montgomery, Alabama, 1972-1973 (Box 402)
    - Newark, New Jersey, apprentice trainer evaluation (Box 402)
    - Newark, New Jersey, T, 1975; training (Box 402)
    - Omaha, Nebraska, 1976 (Box 402)
    - Paterson, New Jersey, 1974 (Box 402)
    - Salt Lake City, Utah, 1974 (Box 402)
    - Toledo, Ohio, 1973 (Box 402)
    - Trenton, New Jersey, circa 1971 (Box 402)
    - Tulsa, Oklahoma, 1973 (Box 402)
    - Wichita, Kansas, 1972 (Box 402)
    - Adult Basic Education (ABE), 1973 (Box 402)
    - Bagwell, Ben, 1973 (Box 402)
    - Budget, 1973-1975 (Box 402)
    - Census-ABE, undated (Box 402)
    - Correspondence, 1973; 1975 (Box 402)
    - Correspondence, circa 1973-1975; 2 folders (Box 403)
    - Evaluation, 1975 (Box 403)
    - Evaluation forms, 1975 (Box 403)
    - Form letters, 1973 (Box 403)
    - How to Start a Volunteer Literacy Project (Box 403)
    - Inventory, New Readers Press (NRP), 1974-1975 (Box 403)
    - Job descriptions, undated (Box 403)
    - Library materials, 1973-1974 (Box 403)
    - Metropolitan Expansion Project, Laubach Literacy International (Box 403)
    - Newsletters, Oct. 1975-Oct. 1976 (Box 403)
    - Orientation to NALA-Metro Expansion Projects (Box 403)
    - Record Keeping System, 1974 (Box 403)
    - Reports
      - [General], 1973-1975 (Box 403)
      - Ohio, 1974 (Box 403)
      - [General], 1975-1976 (Box 404)
    - Tutor Training Handbook, 1975 (Box 404)
  - Metropolitan Areas Expansion Project, Jul. 1973-Jun. 1975 (Box 454)
  - Minnesota Right to Read (R2R), 1972-1974 (Box 404)
  - Miscellaneous, 1976-1977; 2 folders (Box 454)
  - Name change, 1977 (Box 454)
  - National Conference Leadership, 1974 (Box 404)
  - New Streamlined English/Teaching English as a Second Language (NSE/TESL) / Lane, Martha, 1972-1975 (Box 404)
  - Newsletters
    - [General], 1972-1973 (Box 404)
    - Alaska-Hawaii, 1969-1963 (Box 404)
    - Idaho-New York, 1969-1983 (Box 405)
    - Ohio-Washington, 1969-1983 (Box 405)
    - Literacy Leadership/Literacy Intercom. merger, 1974-1975 (Box 405)
    - NALA Leadership; Literacy Leadership; Literacy Intercom), 1967-1976 (Box 405)
  - Nominating Committee, 1973-1975; 2 folders (Box 405)
  - Oregon Literacy Inc., 1972-1973 (Box 405)
  - Organization and administration, 1975-1976 (Box 405)
  - President, 1974-1975 (Box 405)
  - Promotion and Public Relations Committee (Box 405)
  - Promotion Committee; Hanson, Marilyn, 1972-1974 (Box 405)
  - Promotion Kit, Baton Rouge, Louisiana, undated (Box 405)
  - Publications Committee, 1972-1974 (Box 405)
  - Recording Secretary, 1974 (Box 406)
  - Regions
    - [General], 1973-1976; 2 folders (Box 406)
    - Eastern Canada, 1977-1979 (Box 454)
    - Eastern Canada, Nova Scotia, 1973-1974 (Box 406)
    - North central; Kennedy, Mildred; Dooley, Thelma, 1973-1975 (Box 406)
    - Northeast, 1977-1979 (Box 454)
    - Northeast; Borei, Sven; Merimam, Scott, 1973-1975 (Box 406)
    - Northwest, 1977-1979 (Box 454)
    - Northwest; Entler, Martha; Lowd, Mabel, 1973-1974 (Box 406)
    - South central; Stephens, Catherine, 1972-1975 (Box 406)
    - Southeast; Pulling, Verne, 1974-1975 (Box 406)
    - Southern California; Bell, Alta, July-Dec. 1967 (Box 406)
    - Southwest, Jun. 23-27, 1983 (Box 454)
    - Southwest; Scanland, Jane; Stolzmann, Esther, 1973-1975 (Box 406)
    - Southwest, meeting, Apr. 8-22, 1975 (Box 406)
  - Research and Evaluation Committee, 1972; 1975-1976; 2 folders (Box 406)
  - Right to Read Proposal, Minnesota, 1973 (Box 406)
  - School tutorial, 1977-1978 (Box 454)
  - Skills books, 1977 (Box 454)
  - Summary Data, Tutors Trained, Workshops Held, Memberships, 1966-1971 (Box 407)
  - Teaching English as a Second Language (TESL), 1975-1976 (Box 407)
  - The Teaching of Basic Reading and Writing Skills to Older Non-readers, circa 1974-1975 (Box 407)
  - The Teaching of English the Laubach Way to Speakers of Other Languages (TESL)
    - Lane, Martha (Box 407)
    - Avery, Bea; Bell, Alta (Box 407)
    - Black, Rolena; Carter, Onalee (Box 407)
  - Training teams, 1977 (Box 454)
  - Trustees, Board of, Metro Projects, 1974-1975 (Box 407)
  - Tutor Training, A Handbook for Tutor Training, Georgia, undated (Box 407)
  - Tutor Training, Tutor-Training Kit, Oregon, circa 1972 (Box 407)
  - Tutor Training, Volunteer Literacy, Virginia (Peninsula), circa 1971-1972 (Box 407)
- New Readers Press
  - Catalogs, 1971-1976 (Box 408A)
  - Price list and description, "English the New Way (Box 408A)
  - Publications
    - A-D (Box 408A)
      Alcohol: Facts for Decisions / Gail Lichtman
      Blacks in Time / Douglas Weeks
      Can You Give First Aid? / Francis M. Bontrager
      Claiming a Right, Stories of Great American Indians / Muriel Ringstad
      Drugs: Facts for Decisions / Roger Conant
    - Be Informed Series (by unit number) (Box 409)
      Personal Credit
      Buying an Auto
      Owning an Auto
      Buying a House
      Renting a House
      Reading Your Newspaper
      Mental Retardation: What is it?
      Are You Ready to Marry?
      Using Measurements
      Wise Buying
      Money
      Drugs
    - English the New Way (series), 2 folders (Box 408A)
      Basic Phonics / Frank C. Laubach
      Learn English the New Way / Frank C. Laubach
      Book I & II
      English 900 'New Spelling'
      1000 Irregular Spellings
      Teacher's Manual
    - G-M (Box 408A)
      Good Manners in the United States / Bengt Simonson & Earl Roe
      Having a Baby: Unwed Mother / Maxine Phillips
      Helping Your Handicapped Child / Ellen Collins
      How to Find a Job / Roger Francis & Sam Iftikhar
      How to Register and Vote / Katie Baer
      How to Study at Home / Henry Ginn
      I Am One of Those / Kay Koschnick
      It Could Happen to You
      Living With the Retarded / Maxine Phillips
      Machine-Age Riddles / Calvin Greatsinger
      Martin Luther King / Willie May Watson
      Martin Luther King, Teachers Guide / Robert F. Caswell & Dianne Novakouski
    - New Streamlined English Series
      - Everyday Reading and Writing / F.L. Laubach, Elizabeth M. Kirk and R.S. Laubach (Box 409)
      - New Ways / Frank C. Laubach & Elizabeth Mooney Kirk (Box 409)
      - Opening Doors / Virginia Stafford (Box 408A)
      - People and Places / Frank C. Laubach & Elizabeth Mooney Kirk (Box 408A)
      - Readings in Literature (draft) (Box 408A)
      - Skill Book 1: Checkups, 1970 (Box 409)
    - News For You (assorted issues) (Box 408A)
    - Our United States, book + workbook (Box 408A)
    - P-R (Box 408B)
      Planning Your Family
      The Pointer, 2 issues (Spring 1972 and Winter 1972)
      Preventing Mental Retardation
      Reader Development Bibliography, April 1974
    - S-T (Box 408B)
      Series on Signs / Sol Gordon (4 volumes: Signs, More Signs, Signs of Our Times, Signs for Teachers)
      Story of Jesus, Part I-III in New Spelling (3 volumes)
      Telephone and Telegraph (Your Personal Business, Unit 1)
      Trouble and the Police
    - U-W (Box 408B)
      Using Language Experience with Adults, A Guide for Teachers / Katherine Kennedy & Stephanie Roeder
      We Honor Them / Willie May Watson (vol. 1-3)
      Why You Need Insurance / George Gillespie & George Wanyee
    - Pamphlets, Laubach Literacy (Box 408B)
    - Publications, other
      - How to Read Maps (Box 409)
      - Readings in Literature (Box 409)
    - Pronouncing Glossary (Box 409)
    - Publishing Committee, job records, 1965-1966 (Box 409)
    - Streamlined English (Box 409)
    - Health pamphlets (Box 409)
    - Teacher's Guide / Sallie E. Cook, 1973 (Box 409)
  - Publications not by New Readers Press
    - Basic Phonetic Reader / Laszlo Hunyady (Box 408B)
    - The Elements of Phonetic Reading / Laszlo Hunyady (Box 408B)
- Newsletters
  - Adult Education News (India), 1959-1960 (Box 454)
  - Adult Literacy News Bulletin (India, Burma, Ceylon), 1949-1957 (Box 410)
  - Asian-South Pacific Bureau of Adult Education, 1966-1967 (Box 410)
  - Epistle to the Koinonians, 1957-1976 (Box 410)
  - Forum, Nov. 1988; Fall 1990 (Box 454)
  - Indian Journal of Adult Education, June, Sept., Oct., 1973 (Box 410)
  - Intercambio, Overseas Education Fund (OEF) (Box 410)
  - Intercom, 1979-1983 (Box 454)
  - Lit-Lit, World Literacy Newsletter, 1957-1960 (Box 410)
  - Lit-Lit, 1961-1966 (Box 410)
  - Literacy Advance, 1986-1990 (Box 454)
  - Literacy Beyond Borders (Laubach Literacy International), Fall 1979; 1985-1990 (Box 454)
  - Literacy Literature, Laubach Literacy Letters, 1943-1956 (Box 410)
  - Literacy Today (Literacy House), 1970-1976 (Box 454)
  - Miscellaneous, 1952-1973 (Box 410)
  - Project Learn, 1984-1986; 2 folders (Box 454)
  - Reading Today, 1985 (Box 454)
  - Religious Journalism (Syracuse University), 1958-1971 (Box 410)
  - Students Speaking Out, 1986-1991 (Box 454)
  - Technical Assistance Information Clearing House (TAICH), 1975-1976 (Box 410)
  - Trainer Touchstone, Nov. 1983-Dec. 1990 (Box 454)
  - The World at Work, 1973; 1975,; 1976 (Box 410)
  - World Education, 1960-1973 (Box 454)
  - World Literacy and Christian Literature newsletters
    - [General], 1951-1956 (Box 410)
    - Africa Newsletter, Dec. 1947-1950 (Box 410)
    - Far East News, 1949 (Box 410)
  - World Literacy Newsletter, Feb. 1951-Dec. 1956 (Box 410)
- Pitts, Edward H.
  - Adult Education, 1958-1970 (Box 411)
  - Assistantships, 1969-1972 (Box 411)
  - Brochures, Laubach Literacy in Action, 1972 (Box 411)
  - California Literacy, 1962 (Box 411)
  - Conference materials, circa 1971 (Box 411)
  - Correspondence
    - [General], 1961-1972; 7 folders (Box 411)
    - [General], Jan. 1969-1973; 10 folders (Box 412)
    - [General], 1972-1973 (Box 413)
    - Ahmed, Naseen, 1968 (Box 413)
    - Caswell, Robert, 1967-1968 (Box 413)
    - Dames, J. J., 1967-1970 (Box 413)
    - Frank C. Laubach bibliography (Box 413)
    - Friberg, Norman, 1967-1968 (Box 413)
    - Friedman, Robert, 1967-1968 (Box 413)
    - Froemming, Paul, 1968 (Box 413)
    - Hudkins, James, 1969 (Box 413)
    - Jijon, Fabiola, 1968 (Box 413)
    - Johannes, Phyllis, 1968 (Box 413)
    - John, A. K., 1967-1968 (Box 413)
    - Literacy Clearing House, 1969 (Box 413)
    - Maitra, Satyen, India, Calcutta, 1968 (Box 413)
    - Meader, Murray, 1967-1970 (Box 413)
    - Memos, 1967-1971; 5 folders (Box 413)
    - Renteria, Ana Maria G. de, 1967-1968 (Box 414)
    - Salmonson, Alta, 1967 (Box 414)
    - Schunk, Jackson, 1968-1969 (Box 414)
    - Shamy, Mohammed, 1967-1968 (Box 414)
    - Shumate, Hazel, 1967-1968 (Box 414)
    - Staff meetings, 1970-1972 (Box 414)
    - Sywulka, Stephen R., 1968 (Box 414)
    - David C. Cook Publishing Company, "The Incredible, Helpful, Hopeful, Growing, Changing Sunday School., 1975 (Box 414)
  - Financial
    - Budget, 1970-1973; 3 folders (Box 414)
    - Budget development, 1973-1975; 3 folders (Box 414)
    - Budget request, 1975-1976 (Box 414)
    - Fund raising, 1967-1972 (Box 414)
    - Investment statements (Box 415)
    - Miscellaneous, 1971-1972 (Box 415)
    - New Readers Press, 1967-1968 (Box 415)
    - Proposals, 1965-1971 (Box 415)
  - Founders Kit, 1962-1963 (Box 415)
  - Goals and objectives
    - Brace, C. Millar, 1977 (Box 416)
    - Blakely, Cynthia, 1971-1977 (Box 416)
    - Butler, Trudy, 1971-1973 (Box 416)
    - Caswell, Robert F., 1971-1977 (Box 416)
    - Cook, Dennis, 1972-1977 (Box 416)
    - Gipson, Priscilla, 1971-1976 (Box 416)
    - Gridley, Nancy C. (Box 416)
    - Jakes, Cynthia Stradel, 1973-1977 (Box 416)
    - Koschnick, Kay, 1971-1977 (Box 416)
    - Laubach, Robert S., 1971-1974 (Box 416)
    - Loveland, Robert A., 1971-1973 (Box 416)
    - Morris, Alfred J., 1973-1974 (Box 416)
    - Morris, Fred, 1971-1974 (Box 416)
    - Nace, Morton, 1971-1977 (Box 416)
    - Pitts, Edward H., 1971-1973 (Box 416)
    - Stauffer, John, 1971-1972 (Box 416)
    - Stradel, H. Robert, 1973-1977 (Box 416)
  - Intermedia, Film Questionnaire, 1976 (Box 415)
  - Liberia, 1954 (Box 415)
  - Literacy, 1953-1956 (Box 415)
  - Memorial Fund, Frank C. Laubach, circa 1971 (Box 415)
  - Miscellaneous, 1961-1976; 2 folders (Box 415)
  - Missions Advanced Research and Communication Center (MARC), 1974 (Box 415)
  - National Affiliation for Literacy Advance (NALA)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 415)
    - Correspondence, Southern California, 1966-1971 (Box 415)
    - Correspondence, Southern California; McMillan, May, 1967-1970 (Box 415)
    - Oregon Literacy, 1969-1970 (Box 417)